All right well everyone and this is what's new in javascript
for fast and scalable applications my name is brian troublesome
in a program manager at microsoft work on the
...javascript engine which is the javascript engine that
power's microsoft edge as well as your windows applications...html
and javascript...tweet occasionally you can follow me there and do stuff and get hub
...watch that as well and certainly feel free to email
me if you have questions later about any of the content here?
So, today me to go over some of the new stuff that's coming to ecma
script six that's the new version of javascript the latest
a standard it's not quite ratified yet but it's coming
and then I'll do a deep dive into the some advanced a
sync programming patterns using these new...six features namely
...promises iterate errors and generators and,
then switch gears and talk about some new stuff that's coming to
javascript some upcoming stuff that were partnering with
...working withmissoula and intel to deliver on talk about that or towards the end.
yes, six at transcript six recently renamed to
...script twenty fifteen so if you're seeing us twenty fifteen out there it's same thing
...it's done it's been in progress for six years now I guess and
it's finally, finally complete and depending on how you measure
it's perhaps the largest update to javascript its history the...spec
...just balloon in size it's just massive and, we're doing the committee was
working hard for those six years, you know, it's there's a lot of lot
...new stuff in it going forward though if you take a look at this
little graphic here future updates to ecma...going to be much smaller and,
that's because the committee is moving to train models so that was the rationale behind renaming
...sixty ftwenty fifteen is that there's going to be
an twenty sixteen and twenty seventeen and twenty eighteen hopefully
twenty two hundred, you know, out into the future.
So, that's super exciting networks really nice with edges
sort of planmicrosoft edges plan to be evergreen so,...is will be
...you...language features much more rapidly.
...scripts kind of unique it comes with a test suite as well it's actually
a language...within official test suite that's owned by the standards body and, the
cool thing about it is you can you can help so yes,
six coverages coming it's not all...yet there's a lot of people that are working to get the
fsix coverage there if that's something you're interested in helping out with there's,
there's a lot of opportunities to dive...learn about...six stuff that way and certainly
if you find any bugs in this yes six in any of the sixty...today or any of
that you're trying all of the implementers run this test suite so it's a great way to.
To get those bugs fixed.
Incidentally the slides...notice...not using powerpoint amusing edge this is.
Written using all the...six...could consider my side somewhat of
a demo as well little bit fancier than...you'll see.
So, microsoft edge...the six ...has been working hard on
the building out as much of this functionality as we can and,
as a result we actually have the highest score among browsers on the fsix
compatible and can't see the numbers but I think we have about eighty one percent yes
six compatibility ish so, we've just made a ton of progress
and what that means is actually most of the six you can use in microsoft edge today but,
we're not actually just sort of chasing this
golden one hundred-percent we're doing
what I would term more interoperability driven standards developments
where actually being really careful and deliberate with implementing these new features to make
sure that we don't break the web breaker code introduce
new differences between browsers they have to worry about and that kind of stuff and,
what that might mean is in some cases we take a lot of data that to the
...and say hey we actually can't implementssay arrayed on prototype
...the contains a because that breaks the web and, that was actually real case
...a breaks and older versions of new tools...so we had to while neck case the
fixes just...includes and it turned out that works but basically
...being deliberate here and making sure that we can give you all these nice
new features without also causing pain another in other areas?
And, not just working on the current standard the fsix...also looking towards the future so, there's as
...js that you can turn on in microsoft...right now in about
...seemed is coming through soon I'll talk about those towards the end
...that doesn't make sense yet.
All right so how many people are using any fsix it on your programs right now?
Not too many maybe you just actually handful how many people using promises
whether nj query or ok good that's a that's a much larger number.
So, yes, six
plus asic programming is awesome and that's and that's for a few reasons
...functions are greatpromises are built...language now so you don't need a
library to use promises anymore and iterated...
generators to combine to make some really awesome patterns social you step-by-step how that works.
So, era functions are new function syntax added to javascript...a new
...to make functions but the nice part about era functions is that they're super
...there's just an arrow I'll show you what it looks like this
just super small always anonymous so terse is actually no way to give
...a name course you can assign it to a variable but,
one of the most useful aspects of...functions is that this and
arguments and super inside of that era function is the exact same as it is outside of the
...function so the...function doesn't change the value of thisit just uses
...outside so, no, more aliasing this to the apps
...self or whatever so, let's look at that looks like.
And, I want to some I want multiply each element of this array and,
multiply by multiply by two and some so, let's update this to use
era function second show you just how awesome...functions are.
...save the old codes we can compare more directly.
All right so actually let's start with this codes can just
edited on-the-fly so, the first...functions you don't need the function
...get rid of it to me letters you also don't need the parens around
arguments list if you only have one arguments you don't you don't in the parens if zero or to
...still needed but with just one you don't and,
now comes the only boiler plate with error functions the nice equals greater than?
And, now for...function body if you just have one expression in
their body and you don't need to and,
you want to return it you can actually just get rid of the braces and get rid of the return and
I'll actually just return the value of that expression
for you so this is the exact same as this
with substantially fewer characters and it's just much easier to read.
We can do the same thing here that we have to parameters we do need to keep the parens
but followings similar process.
We end up tests and if we run it in the proper result...with error
functions you spend a lot less time just writing the function keyword for one
thing but it's also just syntactically a lot nicer to read and to...maintain.
So, let's look at a case where you want to do something sort of asynchronous.
So, here we have a dog object and we want to
the dog object can bark but, you can also bark later and we do this via set
time-out and after this call back we call
bark on the this object so...run this
...works fine second later he works smart dog but,
...have this sort of underscore this nonsense...nice
get rid of that so let's do their similar processing clean it up so we have.
We have zero are arguments are parameters so we do need to have the
prince there but we can get rid of the braces?
Can move this?
Ok, so, this point this works this works fine but,
we can even go a step further and realize that because this inside of this era function
here's the same as it is outside this aliasing we don't even need anymore so
we can just get rid of this completely ans delete
the underscore and it just works there so there's no more underscore this
self aliasing nonsense
...just plain works so this is just super potent
for asynchronous code where you really need this to stay the same
...can call methods on your on your object after some asynchronous task is...
...are the same way so, in this example you know, this argument's object
here is going to be the arguments to this test function and not the
argument's to get...so it's going to be two arguments here instead of zero...run it would
you see that is the case.
Seo functions can actually have bodies they can have blocks that's fine but,
not that when I run this guy get undefined and that's because when you do use the block with
the...function then you do
need the explicit return it won't it won't automatically return the last
statement for you so with that it works.
So, here's an interesting case.
Have a function called...and, I just want to log the result of
it so I just want to see...by show of hands how many people think I'm...some kind of object right now?
And, how many people think...something else like say
undefined or null or something crazy?
And, the naming should give you...a little bit of a clue but...fifty so,
this is actually...undefined and that's because these curly braces...
blocks they are not is not an object even though it looks exactly like an object
is the block with a labeled statement and there's no return in here so it
just returns undefined this is a gotcha...you I promise you can put.
Return in there and you can see it returns brian so,
the fix this just know that when you returning an object
it with the implicit returnof the...function just...parens.
So, era functions really it really helpful with your
in a synchronous code a c code is sort of the hallmark basing code is just tons and
tons and tons of function call back so air functions...help with them.
Another big help for is encode is promises I know a lot of you are already using promises for
the that those that aren't just one explain
them briefly and hopefully demonstrate how helpful they can be for your
...encode so conceptual model of a promises it's an object that the
produces that a producer of some asynchronous value will give the consumer
and that object represents and the future value so,
promises like a single value that just hasn't been fulfilled the promise for value so,
producer when it needs to produce some kind of
asynchronous value rather than taking a call back
that we'll call it some later point in time returns a promise and the producers
also holding some resolve and reject functions that can use to fulfill
the promise with some kind of value or reject the promise with some kind of error?
And, then...the consumer side when you call in asynchronous api you get out
of promise and...can listen for when the producer calls this when the producer
fulfills...rejects by using the...in the...catch methods?
The promise has three states...is born into the world pending and,
then once the producer decides...has a value for the promise that will
...or maybe some error occurred or reject it and,
once it enters ...rejected it will never change and,
that's really nice becauseif a promises resolved and it's just sitting out thereyou
can come by later at any point later in your program attaches
...handler and get immediately called with the value of
that promise so let's look at some examples of using promises so here we have the
sort of producer and this producers going to produce a
value of undefined after some amount of time so we do that by returning
a new promise and notice that the promise constructor takes a function
...kinda weird it's called the revealing constructor
...basically this constructors going to call this call
back immediately with resolve and also reject which I'm not using in this case.
But, so, you get called back and.
So, we're just going to set timeout and.
We're going to resolve that promise after some number of milliseconds.
So, the.
The other on the consumer side of the promise.
Moi edges and starting...
...now this is where this is never happen in any of the any of the dry runs.
Very impressed actually don't know why it it's not letting me actually restarted.
Probably because I need to remove these hung processes.
I suspect on security is that will work.
So, let's see.
Excellent.
Search zoom back.
And, remember that's nice.
Okay, so, remember that this is the producer up here so,
on the consumer side rather than passing a call back to this time-out
We just get a promise back and then we use this dot then method to
listen for when the promise resolves so if you run this guy and we see...in a second
letter we see and because the producer results the promise after...so we can create numerous
of these promises and they all just sort of play together nicely.
So, let's do something real here we have some code
...wrapper around xml http requests get and,
then we want to use it to get the top posts from...called x
...let's change to use promises so first thing you don't need to use the call back we can delete that.
And, when or producer and we want to produce some kind of asynchronous value the first thing that we usually want to
use return you promise?
And, this gets resolved interject functions.
Just kind of boiler plate they get really good at typing.
Ok, so, now than rather than calling this
...back which we don't have anymore we're going to call the result function we
have a successful result and we don't need to pass
the error value we just don't say anything about the error because there was no error
that's really nice part about promises likewise when we
rejects we just say hey we have an error we don't need to tell anything about
what the value is like in this case as providing known we can just get rid of it.
that's...producer sites actually pretty quick to convert to promises...the producer side.
So,...consumer side rather than passing a call back which is
called the function and we get a promise we can call...than on it and here we
don't even worry about error handling because then is only going to be called if there was an error?
So, we can just put this.
...success
the result right in there and then for error handling we can use...pretty straightforward.
...the...message.
So, now I've got pretty much the same exact code
...had before but instead using promises so you can run it so you
get the top the top posts from reddit now the cool thing about this
is like say I wanted to get the top posts from the javascript separate well that
...link is wrong...clearly I mean...to do that but, also is an
...advantage over the call back code say
like I got some malformed json back from the server and I ran it.
I can actually catch that error to says see the error has actually popped
out of this than and propagated down the chain until it found a cache so that's one of the really,
really useful aspects of promises that errors in values...sort of propagate down the promise
chain in a...the synchronous imperative kind of way.
So, here's a more complex example same get
helpers before but this time what I want to do is I want to get the top posts from the javascript
separate and then I want to get the top comment from that post.
So, when you're doing this with...echoed a lot of times the end up having to nest to nest
your call backs together and you just end up using up all kinds of horizontal
...space and your program ends with like fifty million
of these guys and I know we've all seen programs that do this
...like...we don't it's
been nice to avoid all of that and promises have a really cool feature that lets you do that and,
it's one of the being reasons why using
promises awesome so this code works like this code is fine I can inside of this
outer then handler I can create new promises and do more stuff that's fine but it
actually works out better if we return the promise from the from...handler?
...that does is it says hey any change promises.
Any chained then.
The value that promise resolves to that is the value of this
...parameter here.
Will be whatever this promise resolves to here?
So, using this.
You can just chain all of your operations together and you don't need to use up any
intense space or anything like that it just
more less works so errors work the same way they just propagate down.
Propagate down the...we could handle errors once.
And, this will handle any errors that occur in the network
request from get any errors that occur pulling out data from
the json any errors that occur in a second like all of this all of this is handled
by the single dot catch that's just a huge improvement over call that code.
So, as I mentioned promises are now part of the platform you don't need you don't need a
librarian to get to take advantage of some of these really nice code improvements that you
get from promises but if...already using a library or you prefer to use a
library because they come with the vast number of helpers and control flow tools and that kind of
thing you can do that actually
the built-in promises the standard fsix promises will interoperate with
...promise libraries without issues so you can return a j query promise from
...handler standard promise or vice versa and that's just going to work for you and,
that's really important is libraries actually will have their own
promised dependencies and sometimes you can end up with three or four different types of promises
in your program that work that's fine.
But, I think one of the most
in the awesome reasons why promises being in the platform is great is that don api
...return promises so no more are done api is going to be taken call backs for
...stuff, for example, web crypto is new api for doing cryptography
...the stuff they returns you promises rather than taking
...likewise the new service worker spec the fetch api is kind
of like a x hr request but it returns promises rather than taking this crazy call
that thing so promises being part of the platform means if
your code is using promises you just don't hardly have to do any work everything...sort of place together.
...another nice reason is once things get built-in browser vendors will start to get better at
tooling and performance answer expect those to improve in the future as well.
All right so the next thing I want to talk about is integrator is innovators are step along the way to generators...talk about
...first.
Innovators in javascript ...conceptually the same as they are in any other language might be useful
it's just a protocol for a consumer to pull multiple values synchronous
...from a producer.
So, javascript accomplishes this iteration protocol by using three interfaces
the called interfaces but actually interfaces aren't part of the
...have borrowed the syntax from the type
scriptures to describe the shape of the interface all interfaces to javascript
is an object with a certain number of properties that's basically it so, this is
...interfaces the first interface that's part of this iteration protocol and
all that is a special method that the symbol that iterate or name that returns
and integrator so if you want your object to be...you just implement the symbol
that iterated property or return a new fresh integratorthat you can use to
keeppulling values the thing they used to pull values is...interface
...required to have a next method there's also return and throw which you can use for
more...cases but those are optional on need is a next method and,
that makes you...integrator as far as javascript is concerned so many call the next you get out
of result the way you can check whether you're done or not is that this
result has a boolean property done that tells you whether you're done or
...it also has a value property that tells you...current values and that's all there is the
stray interfaces combined produce this nice iteration protocol there's a bunch of new
language features that except intervals now there's the new for of loop that you can use
to iterate over any old
...there's a spread operator that can,
for example, paths.
Every element of an interval to a function...individual
arguments to function a array that from will take any it herbal and
convert it to an array obviously be careful with infinite a...like if
you arrayed out from the sinatra he'll probably...memory and,
maps insets constructors like if you had an interval of key value...you could
initialize a map using that eventually language features produce...so
arrays obviously there errol the way that's accomplishes this read-out prototype
...values which gives you an interval for the values of a particular array maps you can
iterate...values and entries, entries are just key value...and
...likewise you can iterate values so let's look at how this...
...a simple example of an array and I just want
to log each item of the array pretty straightforward.
So, how does this work well...look at this array?
And,...and for of loop will say okay I need you to
...so it's going to look for a special symbol that
...property...going to find it on a rate up prototype.
And, it's going to call it and that's
going return integrator and then for of is just going to call that next and that integrator until done
is true passing each value to the loop so it's a nice easy way to iterate.
Likewise maps...simple map here with two entries
this default iteration scheme works the same way as array the default iteration
scheme of maps key value pairs but you can actually customized this by saying,
for example, values and then you just get the values of the map you can also do
keys and just get the keys of the map so this is really the easy way if you have an
object anyone...multiple iteration schemes you can do it this
way just like maps...just have methods named after the iteration scheme that you want to expose.
So, let's actually get a better understanding of
...by and implementing one from scratch.
what I want to do here is I want to long zero to four and let's sort of do this by
running it and doing what we fixing all errors?
Okay, so, the first-year we see is we don't have a simple
iterative property okay so it's going to call counter for...going to call counter of five and it's going to expect that
thing that this returns is an interval okay so we need to return some objects.
That has...integrator method.
Okay, and, just for simplicity sake we're going to return the same object.
We don't need to do all kinds of crazy nesting.
Ok, so, now the next air that's complaining about is
...doesn't have the property or method next well that's because
we're not satisfying the integrator interface we need to implement next on this guy.
...it done.
Unable to get the
...looking for done on something and now the problem is the for of
lupus called next it's done on define from...just doesn't know what to do so
...that's rightfully confused okay so we need to actually give it a
...saw implement that now.
All right and now if I run this everything works returning
iterated results from this next method which makes me...adverse symbol that
iterative property which returns iterate...and that makes me an...so it's a little
...complicated but that's how you would implement and integrator from scratch.
So, the good news is actually you don't need to do that for the most part you can actually just use
...generators also known as generated also known
as generator functions are functions that return multiple values
and they do that by being intolerable and the by
...returning...when they're called so if you think about
a normal function when you call it it's going to execute every statement
of the function until it hits a return and then that will come out of the function with
the generator function when you call the generator it actually doesn't run anything it just gives you an integrator and
then...call dot next on the integrator that's when the generator body starts running but then rather
than looking for a...state and it's looking for a yield
and every single time it sees a yield...is yielded will come out of the next and the generator will
suspend...just wait there for the consumer to call the next again.
So, generators fundamentally just make...innovators nicer in fact there's it's
so nice that and useful that you probably
won't like that handling code that I had you probably won't ever have to write...your life thankfully but,
this it turns out that this core capability that generators...language of being able to
suspend the function body until later is all you need to actually get
a encode to be even better than it is with promises so let's take a look.
All right so first let's start just by understanding generators...notice that we have this function
Up here the star as with signifies that this is a generator function and not
a normal function so, we can try running it and
...running after trust me that there's no air and that's because
unlike the integrator thing generators always return
in integrator so this is just an empty generator body and, I call counter.
...next on that...done of true immediately
...the for of loop is just saying okay you're done right away so I'm not I'm not I'm not going to
log anything for you there's nothing there so, the way this works is four-hour will get out the error call necks
...generator rule run until there's a yields so we could put the whoops.
Could for...in there?
So, now we get one yield to.
...okay that's not the right way to do that the right way to do this is.
So, there we have the exact same semantics more or less as the
iterate or code from previously implemented in one-line although I think js
and would complain...would make it three lines but regardless
much more simple no messing around with manually returning any of those
...interfaces the generator takes care of all of it
for us so, that's really nice?
So, now I have kind of a little bit of
...understanding of whatgenerators can do?
Let's actually use it to team asynchronous code in
an a really awesome way...time-out function is backward
...use that as a motivating example here.
So, here's the here's the code that we want to riot.
The code that we want to...is to...some value or do some synchronous task and then we
want to wait for some amount of time now and then we want to do some more stuff?
Maybe want to do that a couple more times just so it's clear.
All right so you might notice that this code looks pretty close to if you're familiar
csharp it's pretty close to what you might...inside of an asic function and a single
weight style of programming here except instead of yield
...or instead of...so, that's kind of what I'm trying to get to here is by
yielding promises out of this generator I want to just wait and not run the generator keep
the generator suspended until the promise resolves and then the
...back up again and spawn is what's going to be responsible for doing that so let's actually implement spun.
Case the first thing that we need to do is get the integrator from the generator so recall
...this doesn't running code this just gets the just warms up the generator and
suspended immediately the for runs...
We need a function that's going to get the next value from the generator.
And, since...asynchronous fundamentally...it's easier if
it's function rather than trying to do it with loops.
Okay, so, the first thing we need to do is get the next value.
Entered next.
Ok, so, now I've got the next value out of the generator so whenever I do this
I need to check whether I'm done...so current
...is an...iterated result so first I want to check if we're done.
Handle that later that's less interesting at this point
...if we're not done that means that this generator body.
Scroll down...keep looking at the generator body that means that this generator body has
yielded me something so it's yielded me actually a promise so...that value is a
promise and now I need to tell-all spawn somehow to
tell the generator to the to pick back up where it left off as soon as the promise results
and you do that without then is how that's done so then is going to be cong when this promise that is
...are the generator return or resolves and...need to just take forward again?
And, this will then get the next value out of
...analogy continue until we're done so at this point if I run it.
All goes according to plan it should work.
So, I've successfully implemented tag...spun.
But, I'm still missing this return value for one thing so,
let's just do that quick so this return value isn't produced
until after some launch an indeterminate amount of time basically...asynchronous
lee produced value and...passing this generator despondent clearly spun is going to
have to be the one to give me this return value and respond is going to
be returning me some value asynchronous...so...that's the case
whatever's going to produce evaluate synchronous...we're going to...return new promise?
Okay, and, this is going to be the promise for the return value of the generator and
return value the generator comes out as the value of the iteration result
when it's done so then we can just do you?
We can just do
...dot value actually resolve
...value and now
we've resolved this promise that I return from spawn with whatever value the generator
So, we can do the say here instead that then.
Got return value.
If...did everything right.
Which see one-two-three and return value of done ...work...I do?
The on.
Well, it's not obvious what I've done here.
No, the return value is when I yield you get done
of false always and when you return that's when you get done of true and then
what every return from the generator that's what's going to be...value?
Yeah, that's what I'm doing I just have a string here.
Thank you.
New code reviews that's why like coding is fun okay now it should work yes
excellent okay thank you.
So, that's really cool this is actually just the start of what you can do with this so you can actually make
yieldreturn or rather than give a value...so that's what I'm showing here
is you can actually ...equal this value time-out doesn't resolved anything but say the
time-out promise resolved to a value all we could plan that through pretty easily
by saying hey take takes a value ...that into dot next that's
...comes out of the yield and then this promises going to resolve by calling
...with that values so I mean that's pretty much done I don't have an example of that and,
you can also say hey if a promise rejects make yield
...error that's what those other that error and return methods on the
...interface that I was explaining earlier that's what you can use those for so you could say instead of internet
next you could say it out throat and then in your the generator body you can
handle errors with try catch rather than using promise call backs.
So, this is just super nice to be able to use
...like a and doing asynchronous code but I'm not using any call backs are not using any of
that stuff that's very close to a single...in fact it's so close
that like we have almost all of the useful semantics facing...the only thing that
we need to do really is build in the spawn function and
change the yield keyword to...and actually that's what we're going to do for
the next version of javascript hopefully asic functions will be in yes,
twenty sixteen or certainly soon after and, that
...just be syntactic sugar for this really awesomepattern for asynchronous code?
So, that's generators.
The generators and iterated ears and promises and
...functions these are all-new yes six features that can really help
clean up your in synchronous code can make your...encode just significantly
...you can...so much easier to read you can just do huge
...chains of operations without having to worry about you know,
matching up all of your close cruelly close paren things so it's yes
...just makes is your ace encode just so much nicer?
So, with that take step away from the
...six stuff and talk about some of the progress in microsoft
edge in some new future stuff that's coming to javascript it's not any
...but this is these are more ...things.
The first one I want to talk about is as...js.
...is a optimized
abel low-level subset of javascript so that's impact that and think
about that means we have a sub-set so that means that as mds code is just
...javascript code if your browser doesn't know what as mj asses and it comes across as
...code...run it just fine because it's actually just javascript it's just not going to optimize...can run
it really slowly.
But, the inverse is actually not true most javascript code in fact ninety nine-point
nine percent of javascript code is not valid as...code
...a very tiny subset and as a result this as
...stuff is not something that you're going to be handwritingI mean maybe some of you will but I wouldn't recommend it
very difficult.
It serves more as a target for compilers so
they're actually compilers out there right now...is one of them that will compile your
...cplus-plus native code to this as...that will run in the browser
at near native performance how does that work well
as mds code is compiled ahead of time there's no jet
there's nobel us there's no gc that gets you really
predictable solid performance it's very much like you're...native code where you compile
at once and then the machine just runs it there's no runtime getting in the way.
...because the subset...so tiny.
And, geared towards making optimizations possible we can use some really,
really aggressive optimization similar to the kinds of
things that native compilers are doing and this gets us performance wins especially in
...scenarios that's gets us actually really close to the native
performance so with that I want to show a quick demo.
Of what you can do with as...js.
It's got a load.
I'll switch so we can we can...load together.
So, primal defenders is game it's written
...using the unity engine and much of this code is actually
native code and it's been compiled to run on the web using as
...js so here we have
...using web gl and its using...as
...and it's running at super close to natives speeds and play a little bit of
this tower defense kind of dangerous make sure you warn
...from up here for more than a few minutes.
But, anyway, I mean you can see it's really nice and smooth you get really nice graphics in the
performances is great it's really awesome so we've partnered with
or been working with rather.
Missoula on as
...missoula pioneered this technology and we're happy to bring this to
...edge you can actually turn it on right now if you have latest...if you go you
about flags scroll all the way down the bottom there's enable as ingest
...and this primal defenders is out there you can find
it you can play it there's a bunch of other as...gs plus web...web gl stuff
and it's a lot of fun so enjoy that but,
anyway, so, as addresses is really really awesome
technology forgetting us for allowing native code just to run directly on the web.
So, but, there is there's some problems so if you think about your native code you native code
has access to the hardware it has access to the cpu instructions you
can drop into assembly even if you need to and get super low-level
the web platform doesn't have that capability it has javascript so, the only
...access to hardware that you get is sort of mediated by the web platform but, and,
really key technology that is lacking in the web platform is
cindy
...stands for stands for single instruction multiple data and these are hardware
instructions that you multiple calculations but just use a single instruction so,
the way to think about this is...have four numbers and for other numbers...you want to add each pair
of numbers together you could do that with for...operations but it be nice if we didn't needs
...for operations be nice if we could use just one operation to do all those ads
together and that's actually what cindy does with one
simply operation you can ad for numbers to for other numbers and get a vector of the results?
So, this works on anything where you need to apply the same operation to all elements of the vector
the sdts, for example,...rgb year rgb a pixels so, if you're doing
image manipulation kind of stuff multimedia that's a great opportunity for
...usually...xyz or xyz w coordinates another
example of something that can be easily translated to...or even just arbitrary length
...where you can just take chunks of for off of this
array and process them and chunks you basically get a for...
So, intel we've been working with intel to build cindy into
...run into microsoft edge it's not available yet but it will
be soon so this machine here is actually an experimentaledge build
...experimental build and I do have cindy enabled on it so I can actually demonstrate.
...can do for us.
Okay, sorry I'm extremely close it.
On the network is down...any secondly worth I promise.
Actually we don't need primal dissenters opening anymore doing.
The demo...
...same right doesn't.
Also happens when you're running even experimental os there goes all right so
cindy.
We are.
Ok, so, this is a mandel brought illustration this is a fractal and we can
render this guy without using cindy notice we get.
...kind of kind of jerky it's not quite as smooth as we'd like especially when we get into more
detailed parts the fractal drops down to maybe nine maybe eight frames per second so let's turn on
symmetry...the exact same hardware.
But, actually taking full advantage of the cpu this is not paralyzed across
multiple cores even this is just using...instructions and now
the animation is really nice and smooth and, it's.
Using this basically the same amount of cpu our so,
that means you get for xf ps improvement in some cases using the same amount of
our from your device means better battery life and,
you can actually compile
...native code that might be using cindy optimizations to run on web platform now.
So, we're super excited
...you to show you cindy it's not it's not quite in yet but it will be soon.
So, I hope after all this you take
away is that the future of javascript development is here with the six there's some really great new stuff that
you can do a asynchronous ramming especially benefits from
the fsix with those new with promises being built in you don't need a library more
arrow functions typing function keyword all the time that's all gone
...generators new capabilities in a language that not only make asynchronous
code nicer but make other things nicer as well like actually iterating things
an edge has just great support for...six stuff right now you can try it out and,
certainly after you do let us know you think you can contact me on twitter
especially and, we've also brought some near native performance the web platform
with cindy and with as...js you can compile
your native code to run on chopper in microsoft edge
...your...speedsso,
with that I'm here for questions also be hanging out at the insider lounge after this
for probably an hour and a half so,...questions.
Sure, the question is glossed over because...
Kind of a hard thing to talk about...you have extra time so
that the question was what is that weird square bracket thing and I assume you're talking about
...the innovators code sample.
Had this.
Let's see right I had this thing right this is your question what
is this nonsense so this is a computed properties so I can actually put
...here this is a property name so I could put foo-foo plus.
Bar and this would make a property name...bar so,
it's called computed properties that's inside of the square bracket and the symbol thing.
Is ...a new thing symbols or a new kind of property that
it doesn't have a string name it's actually just a it's kinda like symbols and ruby if,
you know, if, you know, ruby it's like...unique name every new symbol is guaranteed
to be unique so like I could make a new symbol like this and then there's
the symbol global that has a bunch of built-in symbols and these are what
language knows to look for certain protocols like the iteration protocols built around the
symbol dot integrator there's also a symbol that to string tag which
language will look forward to see what the to string output of an object should be,
for example, so, that's a new year six feature called symbols that's what that's what this?
No, because I mean you could so, you might say like well symbol.
And, you can you could make a property called with the string but,
then the for of loop isn't going to see this thing
...herbal it's not going to satisfy the edible ...need to use the global
the symbol dot iterative property because that's what because this for of loop
...basically going to say you know, if
...the symbol
that integrator then it herbal us, you know,
throw some not herbal error or something so that's
...that iterated property key is what the for of loop and everything else that accepts
intervals is looking for a on your on your objects.
But, the good news is you don't really need to implement...generators.
Other questions yes.
So, the question was for people that are supporting older browsers today how are they
going to migrate over to the six hiring a start taking advantage of this stuff.
So, I think actually one of the most exciting parts of the being a javascript developer right now is
that unlike.
In previous eras when we got new versions of the language
nowthere's this new thing called trance piling
it's basically compiling one version of javascript to another version of javascript
and, the type script does this so you could use...a bunch of the six features
...script and that will compile
that code down to run on yes five or even...that would run all the way
back to eighty-nine maybe even earlier there's also other tools on the while that do this babble is
really popular one that targets rather than the type script language
...quite strictly yes next yes, six and some,...
seven stuff and...will compile your generators and
all your others symbols and all that stuff down to just...five code so,
that's a great way to get started because then you can just checking
yes six in your code base and then as part of your build process you just dump out the
cs five code and that goes up...to production it's
actually really exciting time unlike previously where we had to wait for all of your customers
...have the latest browser today you don't have to do that you can just usethese translation tools.
I wrote myself the much of it
is using yes six stuff on the editor is.
Monaco editor believe it's the same that is on.
...visual studio dot com and also in code I believe the joys
...being a microsoft employees I can just roam around grab codes place.
For now that is.
Only I mean it will be delivered...edge before hits the standard
...the intention is certainly for to be part of standard intel is
chanting that proposal in the expertise and committee and,
then made landing a seven and even so you might get that twenty sixteen.
No, you can use sandia outside of as
in js although I believe in our up-coming implementation of
some...will be tied together you only get the performance benefits of
cindy in as...code but,
the intention is eventually that cindy will be available even outside of...the so
you can there's it's just like you get
this global cindy and then you can call operations on cindy to create
vectors and to do these mathematical operations in parallel.
No, out of victimization there is a separate proposal that actually intel
...working on with missoula called parallel js but,
it turns out of victimization is really,
really hard so,...like in javascript knowing
what a pure what functions are pure what functions don't have side effects is actually a really difficult
problem for the compiler and...victimization depends really heavily and being able to do that kind of stuff.
Anything else yes.
...so, the question was if I want to...deed wooed do my clients need
to using intel processors and the answer is no cindy is
a available fairly broadly I think it's called neon on arm but,
the goal of the cindy proposal that's getting added to languages
to actually target the sort of most common types so,
for example, ...on some architectures might even have five hundred twelve bit
vectors that's not going to be for the web platform the web platforms only going to have
the really common probably...thirty-two x four and in thirty-two
x for vectors to make sure that if developers use it
...likely going to be able to take advantage of that optimization
...their clients machines and, I imagine if you're running the same
...code on a architecture that doesn't supports indeed then legit is just going to
admit slow code and actually do the do the simple thing of
adding each one individually rather than relying on simply the developer won't
have to have to query to see whether symbian supported before...
All right well thanks everyone thanks-a-lot for coming hopefully learned a lot of
the I'll be around so definitely just walk up to me and ask questions and happy to talk about this stuff.